原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
《沼泽怪物》前情回顾
Previously on Swamp Thing...
你觉得亚历克的船爆炸是意外吗
Do you think Alec's boat blowing up was an accident?
你好
Hello?
我觉得时间点很蹊跷
I don't like the timing.
他在追踪这个病的发展
He was tracking the progress of the disease.
他觉得他有所发现
And he thought that he was onto something.
我是杰森·伍德罗博士
Dr. Jason Woodrue.
你跟我说你的促进剂能促进生长
You told me your accelerant would make things grow faster.
促进剂成功了
The accelerant works.
我们还多了满满一医院的病人
But we've also got a hospital full up with people
全都患上了某种吓人的绿色流感
with some kind of crazy green flu.
我会去调查
I'm gonna look into it.
不  你要解决问题
No, you're gonna fix it.
艾比  你绕了个圈
Abby, you circled round.
这地方你检查过两遍了
Been through this area twice.
快点  朗德罗  我想简单快速地...
Come on, Landreaux, I wanna make this as quick and as painless--
你可不想跟我玩追逐战
You don't wanna run from me.
你他妈是什么鬼东西
What in the fuck are you?
你的鞋哪去了
What happened to your shoes?
真奇怪
That's weird.
可能被我落在哪了
Guess I, uh, lost them somewhere.
你这么细皮嫩肉的城市男孩在这里干什么
What's a pretty city boy like you doing out here anyway?
对了  我是在...
Right. Um, no, I was, um...
在沼泽里做调查  然后...
doing research on the swamp and then, um...
着火了
There was a fire.
你都不记得我了  对吗
You don't even remember me, do you?
有点印象
Kind of.
没错
That's right.
我就是那个被你杀死的混蛋
I'm that son of a bitch you murdered.
我非常非常抱歉
I am so, so sorry.
你他妈抱歉
You're fucking sorry?
你死定了
You're dead!
-住手  -死定了
- Stop! - Dead!
不要  住手
Don't! Stop!
我要回来找你  听清了吗
I'm coming back for you, you hear me?
翻译  布塔高能预警
翻译  DustD
翻译  冰岛豆腐
翻译  Sakura的小书包
翻译  SwampSide152
翻译  DerbyNinja
翻译  余欢
翻译  马丁马丁回音山
翻译  沼泽小鱼人
翻译  iLOST
翻译  Serrino
翻译  Sylvia17
翻译  屯栗子
翻译  管家大愚
翻译  小酸奶
时间轴  紫夏
时间轴  西·查
校对  布塔拒绝虫子
校对  屯栗子
后期  渔夫
字幕总监制  布塔
沼泽   怪物
第一季  第三集
我想不通  艾比
I don't get it, Abby.
你把那个小女孩救回来了  对吧
You brought back the little girl, right?
你不是应该庆祝胜利吗
Shouldn't you be doing a victory lap?
我有别的发现  莉兹
I found something else, Liz.
是个人
Someone else.
是吗
Okay?
我想苏西·科尔是被一个人吸引到沼泽的
I think Susie Coyle was drawn into the swamp by a man.
我知道这听起来很疯狂
I know this sounds insane,
但是那里有个人类
but there is a human being out there.
他的整个身体布满了植物和藤蔓
His entire body was covered in plants... and vines.
那苏西想去见他  是为什么
And this Susie went to see him because... why?
她说她被召唤到沼泽去帮助他
She said she was called into the swamp to help him.
说他病了  他需要她
That he was sick and he needed her.
然后  她还告诉我那人的名字
And... And she told me that this person's name...
是亚历克
was Alec.
我操
Fuck me.
是啊
Yeah.
那之后你做了什么
So what did you do?
我不知道该做什么
I didn't know what I was supposed to do.
那里就是场大屠杀
It was a bloodbath out there,
苏西受到了惊吓
Susie was going into shock.
我...
I...
逃跑了
ran.
我他妈逃跑了
I fucking ran.
这事你跟别人说过吗
Have you told anyone else about this?
我不知道应不应该说
I don't know if I should.
真不敢相信
I don't believe this.
怎么了
What?
我得去趟医院  我们能之后再谈吗
I have to go to the hospital. Can we talk later?
好啊  行
Yeah, sure.
特鲁斯特医生和新的疾控中心团队今早到了
Dr. Troost and the new CDC team arrived this morning.
看来你不知情
I take it you didn't know.
他在哪儿
Where is he?
艾比
Oh, Abby.
怎么回事  伊莱
What's going on, Eli?
我们一直在亚特兰大关注这里的事态
We've been keeping an eye on things from Atlanta,
我们认为是时候采取新措施了
we felt it was time for a fresh approach.
嗯  这里的情况不同寻常
Yeah, it's... It's an unusual case.
无论如何  我们需要改变策略
Nonetheless, we need to change tact.
所以我要改用新的给药方案
So I'm starting a new drug regimen.
静脉注射大剂量的万古霉素和美罗培南
High dose IV Vancomycin and meropenem.
两者均为抗生素
你认真的吗
Are you serious?
不行  我已经给他们超量使用抗生素了...
No, I already have them maxed out on antibiotics--
亚凯恩医生  我不是来辩论的
Dr. Arcane, I'm not looking for a debate--
失陪
Excuse me.
为什么要大老远从亚特兰大派一个主管过来
Why send a supervisor all the way from Atlanta?
还来了一个高手
There's another hotshot in the house.
听说过杰森·伍德罗博士吗
You've heard of Dr. Jason Woodrue?
嗯  生物遗传学家
Yes, the bio-geneticist?
他  他绝对不是疾控中心的
He's... He's certainly not CDC.
伍德罗正在太平间里了解详细情况
Woodrue's in the morgue right now getting up to speed,
重新检查埃迪·科尔的尸体
re-examining the body of Eddie Coyle.
据说埃弗里·桑德兰在资助他
Apparently, Avery Sunderland is footing his bill.
埃弗里
Avery...
伍德罗博士
Dr. Woodrue.
仔细看看
Take a close look.
你看到了什么
What do you see?
我看看
Well, the...
肾髓质被异物紧紧包住
renal medulla is severely constricted by a foreign matter.
输尿管芽肿胀  几近破裂
Ureteric bud appears bloated, about to burst.
继续
Go on.
这是测试吗
Is this... A test?
我倾向于征询
I prefer to consult with people
对专业有粗略理解的人的意见
who have some vague understanding of the subject matter.
我知道你是埃弗里·桑德兰派来的
I understand you are supplied to us by Avery Sunderland.
你们是老相识吗
You two old friends?
拜托
Please.
入侵的有机体
The invading organism
以极强的特异性适应了它的猎物
has adapted to its prey with great specificity.
难以置信  它
It's incredible, it's...
部分是寄生虫  部分是食肉动物
part parasite, part carnivore.
但却完全是植物性物质
Yet entirely plant-based material.
考虑全局
Big picture.
你还看到了什么
What else do you see?
我看到了什么
What do I see?
我看到了一个叫埃迪·科尔的人
I see a man named Eddie Coyle,
这个人类在这世上生活过
a human being that lived,
养育了一个小女孩  然后死去
was raising a little girl, then died,
被一种可怕的疾病折磨至死
and was tortured to death by an awful disease.
不好意思  我说了什么好笑的话吗
I'm sorry. Did I say something funny?
不  只是你的
No, it's just your...
你的观点很狭隘
Your view is quite limiting.
-怎么称呼  -亚凯恩医生
- Miss? - Dr. Arcane.
艾比·亚凯恩
Abby Arcane.
大自然是残酷的
Nature is brutal.
生命互相吞噬  这是场你死我亡的较量
Life devours life. It's a battle to the death.
掺杂个人感情会遮蔽科学的远见
To bring emotion to bear taints the scientific vision.
如果这使我有偏见  那不好意思
Well, I'm sorry if that makes me biased,
但在这场较量中我站在人类这边
but I'm on the side of humans in this battle.
所有的生命都是零和游戏  亚凯恩医生
All life is a zero-sum game, Dr. Arcane.
而今天的比分是  植物一分
And today the score is plants, one,
人类零分
humans, zero.
你好  戈登  衣服不错  布克兄弟的吗
Hello, Gordon. Love the suit. Brooks Brothers?
不对  等等  凑近了看又像是...
No, wait. Now that I see it up close, I'm thinking...
-仓库男装的  -我已经告诉你了
- Men's Wearhouse? - Told you.
-无可奉告  -这是个小镇  戈登
- Got nothing to say. - It's a small town, Gordon.
你可以屏蔽我的来电  删掉我的邮件
You can block my calls, delete my emails,
愿意的话还可以取关我
unfriend me if it makes you feel better,
但你迟早得跟我谈谈
but sooner or later, you're gonna talk to me.
我不知道你以为自己挖到了什么料
I don't know what you think you've got,
但那完全是胡扯
but it's complete and utter bullshit.
那为什么你每次见到我都这么慌张
Then why do you act so damn scared every time I come around?
听着  我知道你一直在
Look, I know you've been
秘密贷款给埃弗里·桑德兰
making off-the-books loans to Avery Sunderland.
我要查的人他
It's him I want.
把情况告诉我  我会帮你匿名的
Talk to me. I'll keep your name out of the paper.
但是你这样不搭理我
But you know, when you just ignore me like this,
我觉得有点伤感情
it kind of hurts my feelings.
玛雷储贷社
-稍等一下  -没问题
- Just give me a sec. - Sure. No problem.
终于来了
Finally.
一直在用无线电呼叫你
Trying to get you on the radio.
我们找到了维恩·罗比泰尔的尸体
We recovered Vern Robitelle's body.
验尸官说他的喉咙被撕开了
The coroner said he had his throat ripped out.
吉德里警官在附近水域找到了一个船钩
Deputy Guidry fished a boat hook out of the water nearby.
可能就是凶器
It's probably the murder weapon.
死了两个人  到底发生了什么事
That's two dead bodies. What the hell happened here?
不管发生了什么  你都不该擅自行动
Whatever it was, you shouldn't have acted on your own.
-有个小女孩失踪了  -这不是关键
- There was a little girl missing-- - It doesn't matter.
你太鲁莽了
It was reckless.
你应该遵循规章制度  等待支援
You follow protocol, you wait for backup.
而且我不禁想到  如果艾比·亚凯恩
And I can't help thinking that if Abby Arcane
没有牵扯其中  那你可能就不会这么做了
hadn't been involved, then you probably would have.
亚历克·霍兰的调查进展如何
So where are we at in the Alec Holland front?
没有理由怀疑倒霉之外的可能性
There's no reason to believe that it wasn't just stupid bad luck,
那种老旧的舷外发动机碰上火花
I mean, a spark gets into one of those old outboards,
砰  整个都爆炸了  对吗
boom, the whole thing goes up, right?
我晚点会和埃弗里谈谈
Then I'll talk to Avery later
看他还有没有能补充的信息
in case there's anything else he can add.
如果明天前没有任何新发现
If nothing pops up by tomorrow,
我们就按意外结案
then we close it out as accidental.
妈  我们找到了苏西·科尔
You know, Ma, we found Susie Coyle.
我们找到了她  把她安全地带回来了
We found her and brought her back safe.
如果艾比·亚凯恩没有介入的话
If Abby Arcane hadn't been involved,
结果可能就不会这么好了
this story might not have a happy ending.
她的生命体征良好
Her vitals look good.
血压降下来了
Blood pressure is down.
她有没有醒过
Has she been awake at all?
我接班后没醒过
Not since I came in.
哈伦照顾了她一整晚
Harlan was looking after her overnight.
我猜你已经听说伊莱恶意夺权了
Guess you heard about Eli's hostile takeover.
他就是个混蛋
Guy's a dick.
哈伦  你上班打瞌睡吗
Harlan, are you asleep on the job?
抱歉  艾比
Sorry, Abby.
我知道医护人员
I know caregivers aren't
在你的管理下不应该感染  不过
supposed to get sick on your watch but...
你知道是怎么回事
You know how it is.
哈伦
Harlan.
Harlan?
哈伦
Harlan!
需要抢救  推急救车来
Code blue! Crash cart!
侧身  哈伦  不能堵住呼吸道
On your side, Harlan. Gotta clear your airway.
侧身  侧身
On your side. On your side.
五毫升肾上腺素  两升氧气
Five cc's epinephrine, two liters O2,
执行地西泮苯妥英钠给药方案
initiate Valium Dilantin protocol.
亚凯恩博士  戴口罩
Dr. Arcane, your mask!
马上推轮床过来
Okay, I need a gurney here now!
没事的  哈伦  没事的
It's okay, Harlan. It's okay.
清理他的呼吸道
Clear his airway.
数到三  一  二  三
Go! On three. One, two, three!
-好  让他侧身  -确保他的呼吸道通畅
- Okay, put him on his side. - Make sure you clear his airway.
肿胀可能蔓延到喉咙  导致他的喉咙紧缩
The swelling can get into his throat and constrict his throat.
-你们要确保...  -亚凯恩医生  交给我
- Please make sure you-- - Dr. Cane, I've got this.
操
Fuck!
艾比  出什么事了
Abby, what's wrong?
是哈伦  他染上了那种病
It's Harlan. He's come down with the disease.
靠
Shit.
让埃弗里的秘密去死吧
To hell with Avery's secrecy,
我要进霍兰的实验室
I need to get into Holland's lab
查出他到底在研究什么
and figure out what he was working on.
幸运的话  能指引我找到治愈方法
With any luck, it'll point me towards a cure.
亚力克肯定是查到了什么
Alec had to be on to something.
这是最后一招  但是我唯一的希望
It's a Hail Mary, but it's all I've got.
小心点
Be careful.
好
Yeah.
你看到她往哪去了
You got eyes on her?
一路向北
Traveling the north 40.
帮我个忙
Do me a favor.
什么时候你去蚊子湾
If you ever get to Skeeter Cove,
帮我找找霍兰的船的残骸
keep your eyes out for any debris from Holland's boat.
顺我的意吧
Humor me.
我不是一直顺着你吗
Don't I always?
那你到底什么时候回家
So when the hell are you coming home?
今晚  还是明天
Tonight? Tomorrow?
打到猎物我就回去
As soon as I get a kill.
我可不会永远等着你
Well, I ain't waitin' forever.
我要挂了
I gotta go.
什么鬼东西
What the hell?
我真希望你去看了  卡洛琳
I wish you could've seen it, Caroline.
变异的速度太惊人了
The rate of mutation is just astounding.
听起来简直像是没经过有性生殖
It sounds almost as if the genes are being swapped
细胞间就进行了基因交换
between cells outside of sexual reproduction.
使得基因进化的速度达到了
Which makes genetic advances thousands of times more rapid
我们所预期的数千倍
than we ever dreamt possible,
但不只是因为加速
but it's not just because of the accelerant.
这个地方
There's something...
这个地方的诱变特性很特别
There's something specific about the mutagenic properties of this place.
很高兴看到你眼中的激情
It's nice to see that fire in your eye.
那种对学识渴望的热情
That passion, thirst for knowledge.
我知道在路易斯安那州玛雷逗留
I know an extended visit to Marais, Louisiana,
并不是你遗愿清单上的头等要事  但是
was not high on your bucket list but...
杰森
Jason.
你看到我的药了吗
Have you seen my pills?
我的药  我以为放在台子上了
My pills. I thought I set them on the counter.
你已经吃过药了
That's 'cause you already took them.
你看
See?
给你看
There you go.
都吃了
They're all gone.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们预料到会像这样发作  不是吗
We knew there was gonna be episodes like this, right?
所以  没关系的
So, it's gonna be okay.
我的思维正在逐渐退化
I'm slowly losing my mind.
我们心知肚明
And we both know it.
听我说  亲爱的
Listen to me, sweetheart.
我拒绝接受你的病是绝症
I refuse to accept that your condition is incurable.
因为我拒绝接受自己的生命中没有你
Because I refuse to accept my life without you.
杰森
Jason...
如果我把你也忘了呢
What if I forget you?
不会的
No.
我知道你一直精神紧绷
Listen, I know it's been very stressful
因为艾比在这里
with Abby being in here and all,
让你重新想起了那些往事
dredging up these... Well, the memories.
不过她很快就会离开
At least she'll be going soon.
我只是想让你找回以前的自己
I just wanna see you back to your old self is all.
问题是  埃弗里
The thing is, Avery...
我已经找回以前的自己了
I am back to my old self.
过去十四年我不过是在伪装而已
I've just been faking it for the last 14 years,
那才是问题所在
and that's the problem.
我尽可能地伪装
I'm faking it as hard as I can,
因为如果不那样
because if I don't,
我就会变回以前的自己
I just sink back to my old self.
-桑德兰先生  -怎么了
- Mr. Sunderland? - Yeah?
戈登·哈斯来了
Gordon Haas is here?
戈登·哈斯
Gordon Haas?
他来干什么
What the hell is he doing here?
你跟他说  早上再给我打电话
You tell him to call me in the morning.
先生  我说过了
Yes, I tried that, sir.
戈登
Gordon...
搞什么
What the hell?
戈登  我正在吃晚饭
Gordon, I'm in the middle of dinner.
我有急事
It couldn't wait.
银行已经在问了
The bank's been asking questions.
你清楚我的情况  我谈下了很多投资者
You know my situation. I got enough investors on the hook.
等他们看到我的沼泽研究成果...
As soon as they see the results of my swamp study--
你没听懂我的意思  我不干了
You're not hearing me. I'm done.
我退出了
I'm out.
我都不知道一开始你怎么说服我加入的
I don't know how you convinced me to do this in the first place.
或许是通过一次又一次的回扣
Well, maybe it was 'cause of kickback after kickback,
你个贪婪的混蛋
you greedy little bastard.
如果银行发现
If the bank finds out
我转钱给你个人贷款
I'm transferring funds for personal loans for you,
我会坐牢的
I could go to prison.
这是你的工作
Well, that's your job.
你要确保这种情况不会发生
So make sure that doesn't happen.
拿出男人的样子
So you just man up.
解决问题
Yeah. Fix it.
还有  别再不请自来了
And don't you... Don't you come to my house uninvited again.
不  埃弗里  到此为止了
No. Avery. No more.
你要全还回来  全额还款  否则...
I need it all back. Repaid in full, or...
等镇上的人发现
this town's gonna be awfully surprised
伟大的埃弗里·桑德兰债台高筑
when they find out the mighty Avery Sunderland
他们肯定会惊得目瞪口呆
is actually in debt up to his eyeballs.
给你24小时
You have 24 hours.
实验室研究笔记
你压根想不出有谁
So you don't know of anyone
会想伤害亚历克·霍兰
who would want to hurt Alec Holland?
毫无头绪
Not a soul.
或许他跟一些当地人有摩擦
Well, maybe he had trouble with some locals,
毕竟他是个外人
being an outsider and all?
我几乎不了解他
I hardly knew the man.
我的项目需要一个科学家
I need a scientist for my project.
他正好有空
And he was available.
-有什么好笑的吗  -没有
- Something funny? - No.
我只是从没近距离看过你工作的样子
I've just never seen your professional side up close before.
露西莉亚·凯博  犯罪打击者
Lucilia Cable, crime fighter.
我知道他的遭遇很可怕
I know it is a terrible thing what happened to him,
但如果你想知道的话
but if you need to know,
近来我最担心的还不是亚历克·霍兰
Alec Holland hadn't been at the forefront of my worries lately.
不是吗
No?
玛丽亚又开始睡肖娜的房间了
Maria's taken to sleeping in Shawna's room again.
她总是这么复杂
she's always been complicated.
但你和她结婚时就已经知道了
But you knew that when you married her.
艾比·亚凯恩回来后让她又重新回想起了一切
Abby Arcane's return has brought it all back to her.
你懂的
You know,
好像在过去几个月
it seems like in the past few months,
这整个小镇一直在滑入
this entire town's been slipping down
一个黑色的深渊
some deep, dark hole.
我只知道过去五天死的人
I just know that more people have died in the last five days
比过去五年还多
than in the previous five years.
大家都很害怕
Folks are scared.
我很理解他们
I don't blame 'em.
你真美
You look good,
露西莉亚
Lucilia.
埃弗里
Avery...
每次玛丽亚放你鸽子时我总是很美
I always look good when Maria's cutting you off.
我了解你
I know you.
-你这样认为  -我很确定
- You think so? - I know so.
我了解你  我记得你
I know you. I remember you.
你还记得
You remembered...
我还很想你
And I miss you.
-等下  她在家  -不不不
- Wait. Is she home? - No, no, no.
-她晚饭后从不下楼  -晚饭
- She never comes downstairs after dinner. -Dinner?
-不  -等下
- No. - Wait a minute.
不  不行
No. No.
我
I...
关于亚历克·霍兰的问询你满意了吗
Well, have I satisfied you on the Alec Holland question?
我会告诉你的
I'll let you know.
妈妈
Hi, Mommy.
肖娜  亲爱的
Shawna, my love.
你真的以为爸爸这么多年对你忠诚吗
Do you really think Daddy stayed faithful to you all these years?
你为什么这么说
Why would you say something like that?
他像是那种
Does he seem like the kind of man
能忠诚待人的人吗
who could stay faithful to anyone, really?
别这样说你爸爸
Don't say things like that about your father.
他还爱你吗
Does he even still love you?
肖娜  你这么说太残忍了
Shawna, what you're saying is cruel.
或许他是因为其它的原因留在你身边
Or maybe, he keeps you around for some other reason.
别说了
Stop it!
艾比·亚凯恩
404-826-5290
我能请你喝一杯吗
May I offer you a drink?
我绝对需要喝一杯
I sure as hell could use one.
那我们有两个共同点了
That's two things we have in common.
我
I...
有件事要坦白
have a confession.
他在哪儿
Where is he?
你他妈离我远点
Get the fuck away from me!
别碰她
Leave her.
我就是那个被你杀死的混蛋
I'm that son of a bitch you murdered.
离开他
Release him.
你安全了
You are safe now.
苏西·科尔说你是
Susie Coyle said you were...
亚历克·霍兰
Alec Holland.
艾比
Abby...
那晚我在沼泽里看到了你
I saw you that night in the swamp.
爆炸之后
After the explosion.
你还记得发生了什么吗
Do you remember what happened?
我在燃烧
I was burning.
我是什么
What am I?
一个好人
A good man.
一个科学家  你可以帮我
A scientist. Someone who could help me
找回我认识的那个人
find a way to bring the man I knew back.
我不明白为什么这种疾病要攻击我们
I don't understand this disease and why it's fighting us.
不是攻击
Not fighting.
是反击
Fighting back.
怎么回事
What's going on?
乱成一团了  所有病人都急剧恶化
It's a shit show. All of them are tanking.
-抽搐  痉挛  两人昏迷  -该死
- Convulsions, spasms. Two have gone into comas. - Shit.
哈伦
Harlan.
我们尽了最大努力来控制病情
I mean, we're slamming this thing as hard as we can.
用了最强的抗生素
Strongest antibiotics known to man.
但它还在攻击
But it just keeps fighting.
它不是在攻击
It's not fighting.
它在反击
It's fighting back.
给我两个注射器
I need two syringes.
五毫升硫锉嘌呤
Five cc's azathioprine,
还有五毫升来氟米特乙二醇
second syringe, five cc's leflunomide glycol.
-你确定吗  -确定
- Are you sure? - Yes.
-马上就好  医生  -谢谢
- Right away, Doctor. - Thank you.
哈伦  坚持住
Harlan, stay with me.
谢谢
Thank you.
这到底是怎么回事
What the hell is going on here?
你在注射免疫抑制剂
You're administering immunosuppressants?
抗生素只会让情况恶化
The antibiotics are just making things worse.
他们的免疫系统是唯一让他们存活的东西
Their immune systems are the only thing keeping them alive.
他们永远不可能战胜这个
They're never going to outgun this.
它在以闪电般的速度变异
It is mutating at lightning speed.
我们越是攻击它  它反击得越厉害
The more we fight it, the harder it attacks back.
-叫保安过来  -哈伦  坚持住  别放弃
- Get security. - Harlan, stay with me, stay with me.
我要是失去了你  谁还能对我如此坦诚
I lose you, who's going to keep me honest?
带她离开这里
Get her outta here!
医生  血压在下降
Doctor, the BP is dropping.
190  185...
190, 185...
-温度降到38.3摄氏度  -哈伦  哈伦  哈伦
- Temp is down to 101. - Harlan, Harlan, Harlan.
哈伦
Harlan.
你知道自己在哪吗
Do you know where you are?
你知道我是谁吗
Do you know who I am?
妮琪·米娜
Nicki Minaj.
我是你的狂热粉丝
I'm your biggest fan.
给所有病人注射五毫升的硫唑嘌呤
Five cc's azathioprine,
和五毫升的来氟米特乙二醇
five cc's leflunomide glycol for every patient.
照做
Do it.
感觉怎么样
How you feeling?
-好了点  -不错
- Better. - Good.
我们正在尝试新药  我觉得起作用了
We're trying a new medicine, and I think it's working.
你又见到亚历克了  对吗
You saw Alec again, didn't you?
我想帮他  但我...
I want to help him, but I'm...
我不确定该怎么做
I'm not sure how.
他不明白自己身上发生了什么
He doesn't understand what's happening to him.
他很害怕  孤单无力
He's so scared and he's all alone.
我想我们现在都是孤单一人了
Guess we're both alone now.
我们会解决这些的  好吗  亲爱的
We're gonna figure this out, okay, sweetie?
-好的  -所有一切
- Okay. - All of it.
我保证
I promise.
你需要睡一觉
But you need to get some sleep.
需要好好休息一下
You need a good night's rest.
好的
Okay.
我们早上再谈  好吗
We'll talk about this in the morning, okay?
亚凯恩医生
Dr. Arcane?
非常感谢你帮助我们
Thank you so much for helping us.
不客气
You're welcome.
埃弗里
Avery.
你在这干什么
What are you doing in here?
如果你不愿跟我同床共枕
Well, if you won't come to my bed,
那我只好来找你了
I guess I gotta come to you.
-你有话要说  -对  向你道歉
- You want something. - Yes. To apologize.
我一直漠不关心  我应该早点明白
I've been insensitive. I should've understood that
对你来说艾比的回归
Abby coming back here would
触发了所有这些可怕的记忆
trigger all these awful memories for you.
-这很困难  -我知道  亲爱的
- It's been difficult. - I know, honey.
我不想失去你  玛丽亚
I don't wanna lose you, Maria.
我不想让我们忘记
And I don't want us to ever lose sight
这些年来为之努力的东西
of what we've been working for, all these years.
携手努力
Together.
"携手"
"Together?"
玛丽亚  我们很接近了
Oh, Maria. We are so close.
伍德罗博士  他只需要再多一笔资金
Dr. Woodrue, he just needs one more tranche of funding,
来确定这些加速进程的确切原理
to pinpoint the exact makeup of these accelerated processes.
你需要钱
You need money.
不  具体地说  你还需要更多的我家的钱
No. Specifically, you need more of my family's money.
你知道  我们讨论过的
Well, you know, like we discussed,
一旦人们发现我们的成果
once people discover what we've found,
我们会...买家就会滚滚而来
we're gonna have... The offers are gonna be rolling in.
我们就一生无忧了  玛丽亚
We're gonna be set for, well, forever, Maria.
不
No.
我不同意
I don't think so.
我知道你不习惯听到拒绝
I understand you're not accustomed to hearing it.
但我的回答是不
But the answer is no.
你在说什么  玛丽亚
What're you talking about, Maria?
我刚把伍德罗博士请来这里
I just brought Dr. Woodrue down here.
我们就快取得重大突破了
Now, we are close to a major breakthrough.
是我的钱
It's my money.
我资助你的痴人说梦已经够久了
And I've been funding this nonsense of yours long enough.
我也受够了你把我们的
And I've had enough of you throwing
积蓄浪费在这片沼泽
our life savings into that swamp,
追逐你的宏伟妄想
and chasing your delusions of grandeur.
你怎么了  你在干什么
What's going on with you? What are you doing?
你在干什么  玛丽亚
What are you doing, Maria?
玛丽亚
Maria.
Maria!
你不能切断我的资金
You're not cutting me off!
戴尔瑞餐馆
艾比
Hey, Abby.
很高兴见到你  纯威士忌吗
Good to see you. Whiskey neat?
-加瓶啤酒  -没问题
- And a beer back, please. - You got it.
谢谢  戴尔瑞
Thanks, Delroy.
-改成两份吧  戴尔  -马上来
- Why don't you make that two, Del. - Comin' up.
-谢谢  戴尔  -谢谢
- Thanks, Del. - Thank you.
话说  我听说了医院的突破性进展
Anyway, I heard about the big breakthrough at the hospital.
消息传得真快
Word travels fast.
你开玩笑吧
You kiddin'?
整个镇都在说  你是个英雄
The entire town's talking. You're a hero.
是挺有希望的  但是见到明天病人情况前
It's promising, but I'm not gonna crack the champagne
我也不会过分乐观
till I see how the patients are tomorrow.
好吧  但还是非常厉害  小艾
Yeah, well, it's still damn impressive, Abs.
就像你的其它方面一样令人赞叹
Like pretty much everything else about you.
-别闹  -我是认真的  好吗
- Stop. - I'm being serious, all right?
来回顾一下你的人生吧  如何
Let's go over what you've done with your life, hmm?
你上完了大学  医学院
You put yourself through college, medical school,
足迹遍布全世界
traveled all around the world.
这可都不是小事情
These aren't small things.
你抓住了离开玛雷的机会
You saw the opportunity to leave Marais.
毫不犹豫纵身一跃
And you jumped.
实际情况我更像是被逼迫的
It was more like I was pushed.
记得这首歌吗
Remember this song?
-《灯红酒绿杀人夜》  -对
- Prom night. - Yup.
你得给点唱机换点新音乐了  戴尔瑞
You have to get some new tunes on that juke, Delroy.
-不  别怪戴尔瑞  -不是吗
- Nope. Do not blame Delroy. - No?
都是我的主意
It was all me.
没错  我终于鼓起了勇气
Yeah, I finally worked up the courage.
来吧
Come on.
-不行  我不会跳  我不会  -我知道
- Oh, no. I can't dance. I don't-- - I know you don't dance,
但今晚你得破例
but you're gonna make an exception tonight.
因为我已经等了这么久
Because I've waited this long,
我可不会不跳就走
and I'm not leaving without a dance.
所以
So...
听戴尔瑞的  走吧
Listen to Delroy, let's go.
去吧
Go ahead.
好吧
Okay.
有什么不对吗
Is everything all right?
没什么
Everything's fine.
你能回来真好  艾比
It's good to have you back, Abby.
我的老天
Jesus Christ.
你好  丹尼尔
Hello, Daniel.
你不是来读最新的有声读物的
You weren't here to read your newest audio book,
所以我就擅自做主了
so I decided to take the liberty.
不用见外
Mi casa es su casa.
好久不见
Long time.
而你开始酗酒了
And you've been drinking.
每个人都有自己的生存模式  不是吗
Everyone has their survival mode, right?
我的生存模式就在
Mine's that little town store
那家终于开始卖红带啤酒的小镇商店里
that's now finally carrying Red Stripe.
丹尼尔  这听起来不怎么像生存
Daniel, this sounds less like survival
更像是折磨自己
and more like torturing yourself.
我的确在受折磨
Well, that's me.
不能回家的家伙
The guy who can't go home.
有多久了  至少两三个月了吧
What's it been? Two, three months at least?
来吧  上都  拿出那些卡牌吧
Come on, Xanadu. Break out those cards.
再给我解读一次
Give me one more reading.
好吧
Fine.
最后一次
One last time.
你来玛雷已经八年了
Eight years since you've come to Marais,
在这段时间里  你的卡牌就没变过
and in all that time, your cards never change.
快点
Come on.
我洗牌时  希望你把精力集中在
As I shuffle, I want you to focus
你渴望得到的答案上
on the answers you crave.
当你的任务完成  你的等待也就结束了
When your mission will be complete and your waiting will end.
你能做到吗  丹尼尔
Can you do that, Daniel?
我被困在鞋盒大小的小镇里
I've been stuck in a town the size of a shoe box.
相信我  我只想离开玛雷
Trust me. All I can think about is getting out of Marais.
愚者  是现在
The fool. Present.
倒吊人
The hanged man.
是未来
Future.
而第三个呢
And number three?
命运之轮
Wheel of fortune.
每次都是这张该死的卡牌
That same damn card over and over again.
我敢肯定  这就像蛀牙
I swear, it's like a bad tooth.
-我忍不住去戳  -丹尼尔
- I can't stop pokin'! - Daniel.
再看看
Look again.
它们是相同的卡牌  但这次
Well, they're the same cards, but this time...
这次是逆位
This time they're reversed.
真的吗
Seriously?
那是什么意思
Well, what does that mean?
是好事吗
Is... Is that good?
你要开启新的篇章了  丹尼尔
Something's beginning for you, Daniel.
我不知道是什么
I don't know what.
你最近有新认识的人吗
Did someone new come into your life?
对
Yeah.
你觉得我要等的人就是她吗
Hey, do you think she's the one I'm supposed to be waiting for?
谁
Who?
一个医生  艾比·亚凯恩
A doctor. Abby Arcane.
艾比·亚...
Abby A...
莉兹  是我
Lizzy, it's me.
我觉得我发现了那场爆炸的残骸
I think I found some debris from the explosion.
这是霍兰船上的
This is from Holland's boat.
看起来有人开枪打了他
Looks like someone shot him.
谁啊
Who's there?
你还真有胆子
That was quite a thing you did.
竟敢到我家里
Coming into my house,
侮辱我
disrespecting me,
想在我妻子面前羞辱我
trying to humiliate me in front of my wife.
你不能就这么跑到我家来  伙计
You can't just come into my house, man...
你以为你是谁
Who do you think you are?
我马上要成就一番大事业  戈登
I'm on the verge of great things here, Gordon!
我提出要给你分一杯羹
And I offered you a seat at the table.
你应该感恩戴德
You should be thanking me for the privilege,
-你这个小混蛋  -出去
- you mealy little motherfucker! - Get out!
你知道你该做什么吗  戈登
You know what you gotta do, Gordon.
你要瞒住那笔钱
You gotta cover for that missing money.
然后闭紧你的嘴巴
And then, you're gonna keep your goddamn mouth shut.
或者我可以找媒体
Or I could just talk to the press and
告诉他们我了解的你和秘密会议的事
tell them what I know about you and the Conclave.
你这个蠢蛋
You dumb son of a bitch!
怎么回事
What's happening?
清理现场更方便
Easier to clean up the mess.
我知道你回家了  戈登
I know you're home, Gordon.
那辆褐红色的普锐斯把你出卖了
The maroon Prius is a dead giveaway.
你这样只会搞得更加无法挽回
You're just making it worse, you know.
该死
Fuck.